# **CARLOS NETO**

## **DEVOPS ENGINEER**

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/c-neto/

https://github.com/augustoliks

**Prazil - São Paulo** 

#### **PERSONAL SUMMARY**

Self-learning and Ownership mindset IT professional, with tech skills in Programming, Documentation, and DevOps.

It is a Python programming specialist, experienced in Amazon Web Services, focused on system provisioning, automation scripts, and managing logs pipelines and observability stacks.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## **DevOps Engineer**

## **Trustly Inc. | Online Banking Payments**

Movember 2021 - Current

**♀** Remote

DevOps Engineer focused on Cloud programming tasks and log pipelines development. Responsible for automation and Cloud components configuration in a world system-wide online banking platform.

#### Main tasks carried out:

- Automation scripts with Python and Bash;
- OpenSearch cluster management (RBAC, ISM, templates);
- Logstash log pipelines (Enriching, Grok);
- AWS resources analysis and configuration;
- Kubernetes operation, troubleshooting, and development;
- Knowledge Base documentation.

## Software Developer

### Fotosensores | Speed Camera Systems

April, 2018 - October, 2021

**♀** On-site

Software Developer focused on In-House infrastructure demands. Responsible for microservices development, system provisioning, and observability in a regional system-wide Speed Camera System.

#### Main tasks carried out:

- Python microservices, scripts, and integrations;
- GitLab CI/CD pipelines;
- Observability and monitoring with Zabbix, Prometheus, and Grafana;
- Linux Servers management and packing (Red Hat based);
- Knowledge Base documentation.

# **PROJECTS**

- SFTP Cluster (Trustly Inc.): High available SFTP server with users setup provisioned by Ansible and deployment over Kubernetes;
- OpenSearch RBAC (Trustly Inc.): RBAC roles provisioned by OpenSearch Security Plugin based on Principle of Least Privilege;
- Image Transmissions Module (Fotosensores): Speed camera systems module to send vehicle images with integrity and cryptography built;
- Speed Camera Monitoring System (Fotosensores): Web system focused on speed camera system components observability.

#### **EDUCATION**

Analisys and Development System (High-Education)

**FATEC - São José dos Campos** 

# July 2016 - July 2019

Computer Network (Full-Certified)

ETEC - Cônego José Bento

## February 2016 - July 2017

Industrial Automation (Full-Certified)

ITJ - Instituto de Tecnologia de Jacareí

February 2013 - December 2015

- GitLab Certified Associate Gitlab Inc;
- Python Formation Certified Alura;
- Fluent Pyhon Book.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming

Python Bash

Cloud

AWS

• CI/CD and GitOps

GitLab Github TravisCI ArgoCD

· Observability and Monitoring

Grafana Zabbix Prometheus Loki
Logstash Rsyslog Promtail

Containers

Kubernetes Docker Podman

• Infrastructure as a Code

Ansible Terraform

Messaging and Reverse Proxy

RabbitMQ ZeroMQ Redis

NGINX Traefik